ADEJOH RAHMAT YAKUBU

FCT Abuja | rahab.ra42@gmail.com | 08080558485 | 07061851857

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY.

A reliable Employee & highly resourceful, passionate monitoring and evaluation person with strong background in data collection and management. I bring over three years of experience in the collection of both quantitative and qualitative data, sourcing and training project beneficiaries, proficient in the use of different digital data collection application tools. Highly skilful in report writing, multitasking, building and maintaining relationships with stakeholders with the view to achieving organizational set goal and objectives.

WORK HISTORY

Grey Soft Technologies Kaduna.

May 2022 -- Present

Position: Data Scientist (Intern)

- Data collection using a customized survey.
- Participated in data cleaning and perform basic data analysis.
- Help the company to interpret and manage data to drive action insight.

Helbank International Shipping Services Ltd

October 2019 - 2021

Position: Sales Representative/Logistics Executive

- Promptly respond to customer enquiries in person or via phone, email, mail or social media.
- Quickly and efficiently open customer accounts by accurately recording account information.
- Maintain financial accounts by processing customer adjustments in a professional manner.
- Increased customer base by 30% during the year 2018 due to the delivery of quick service.

Engender Health (USAID/Fistula Care Project) FCT, Abuja

April 2016 - 2018

Operation Support

- Support in the collection, cleaning, monitoring and evaluating data.
- Supported the finance & operations Manager to review payment vouchers & Journal vouchers
- Kept records of customer interactions, processed customer accounts and filed documents.
- Collaborated with the team to quickly resolve customer complaints with the appropriate action.
- Assisted in the computation of log books, documenting records & preparing weekly reports.

EDUCATION

M. A. International Affairs & Strategic Studies	(Certificate In view)
Nigerian Defence Academy	
B. A. (Hons.) History	2010
• 2:2, Second Class Honours, Lower Division	
Nasarawa State University,Keffi	(2006 – 2010)
CERTIFICATION/TRAINING	
Data Analysis	2021
Jobberman Soft Skills Training Certification	2021
IBM Design Thinking	2019
IBM Course Badges	2019
Monitoring & Evaluation	2019
Google Analytics	2019
Digital Marketing/Graphics & Design	2019
Microsoft Office Productivity Tools	2011

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Snow Fairy Cakes Services Abuja

• Volunteer as Executive support/ social Media Marketer

May 2017 - 2020

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Skill in Digital Marketing using SMM, SEO, Google Analytics
- Skill in Graphics Design using (AI, Corel Draw, photo shop & Canva)
- Database Development and management Skills using Ms SQL
- Knowledge on the use of Tableau for Analysis
- Skill in advance statistics using Ms Excel
- Highly Proficient in Computer applications; (MS: Word ,Advance excel, PowerPoint, Google Apps)
- Good Problem Solving Skills
- Good Analytical & excellent Interpersonal skills
- Time Management skills
- Fast learning and Work Ethics skills
- Ability to Multi task.
- Average Skill in web Development using Wix and Word Press.
- Strength: Data Analysis, Training and Facilitation
- Interest: Education, Employability, Youth Transition and Research

REFEREES

Available on Request.